<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Act of the Committee of Estates for contriving the severall troupes appointed to come out of the shires into regiments. 26. November 1643.</title>
            <author>Scotland. Parliament. Committee of Estates.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B05212</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">52529198</idno>
  <idno type="VID">178894</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240898629</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing S1129A</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R183940</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">52529198</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B05212)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 178894)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 2774:33)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Act of the Committee of Estates for contriving the severall troupes appointed to come out of the shires into regiments. 26. November 1643.</title>
                  <author>Scotland. Parliament. Committee of Estates.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by Evan Tyler,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[Edinburgh :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1643]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Imprint suggested by Wing.</note>
                  <note>Initial letter.</note>
                  <note>Signed at end: Arch. Primerose Cler. Com.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the National Library of Scotland.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="corporate_name">Scotland. --  Army --  Recruiting and enlistment --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="corporate_name">Scotland. --  Army --  Organization --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Broadsides --  Scotland --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-07 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-09 </date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-09 </date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:178894:1"/>
            <head>
               <hi>Act of the Committee of Estates</hi> For Contriving the severall Troupes appointed to come out of the Shires into Regiments.</head>
            <opener>
               <dateline>
                  <date>26 November 1643.</date>
               </dateline>
            </opener>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">T</seg>He committee of Estates considering that for the present service of the Countrey there are divers Troupes appointed to be levied, and brought forth of the severall Sheriffdomes of this Kingdome, which are not as yet formed in Regiments, nor designed for any Colonells to have charge over them: Therefore, and for the better ordering and making of the saids Troupes serviceable, The Committee of Estates hath ordained them to be divided in seven Regiments, each Regiment consisting of eight Troupes, and each Troupe of sixtie Troupers, besides the Officers.</p>
            <p>And of the saids Regiments, one to be commanded by the Lord Generall his Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cellencie: for the making up whereof, two Troupes to be brought out of <hi>Ireland, viz.</hi> the Troupes of Major <hi>Bannatine</hi> and Sir <hi>Robert Adair.</hi> two Troupes to be leavied, and leavie Money to be granted for that end: As also the twelve score Horse appoint<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed to come out of the Sheriffdome of <hi>Roxburgh, Selkirk</hi> and <hi>Peeblis,</hi> which will make up foure Troupes.</p>
            <p>One to be commanded by Generall Major <hi>Leslie,</hi> to consist of the three Troupes al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ready leavied: The Laird of <hi>Palmais</hi> Troope appointed to come out of the Sheriff<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dome of <hi>Stirling,</hi> and foure Troups to be leavied, and leavie money to be granted.</p>
            <p>One to be commanded by the Earle of <hi>Eglintoun,</hi> and to consist of the twelve score horse appointed to come out of the Sheriffdome of <hi>Air</hi> and <hi>Renfrew,</hi> which will make up four Troupes: The 200 appointed to come out of the Sheriffdome of <hi>Lane<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rick,</hi> which will make up three Troupes and 20 horse, and 40 horse to be levied.</p>
            <p>One to be commanded by the Earle of <hi>Dalhousie,</hi> and to consist of the six score ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed to come out of the Sherifdome of <hi>Berwick,</hi> which will make two Troupes; The six score to come out of the Sherifdome of <hi>Hadintoun</hi> to make up other two: The six score appointed to come out of the Sherifdome of <hi>Edinburgh,</hi> to make up other two; One of the Troupes appointed to come out of the Sherifdom of <hi>Stirling, viz.</hi> That whereof Sir <hi>William Bruce</hi> is Root-master, and the Troupe appointed to come out of the Sherifdome of <hi>Lithgow.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>One to be commanded by the Lord <hi>Gordon,</hi> and to consist of the twelve score horse, appointed to come out of <hi>Aberdene</hi> and <hi>Bamf,</hi> which will make up four Troups: The six score appointed to come out of <hi>Elgin, Narne,</hi> and <hi>Inner-nesse,</hi> on this side of the <hi>Nesse,</hi> which will make up two: And (in regard there are seven score appointed to come out of the Sherifdome of <hi>Forfar</hi>) of six score thereof which will make up two Troupes.</p>
            <p>One to be commanded by the Lord <hi>Kirkudbright,</hi> and to consist of the six score ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed to come out of <hi>Wigtoun</hi> and <hi>Kirkudbright:</hi> The six score appointed to come out of <hi>Dumsreis,</hi> and the twelve score appointed to come out of <hi>Perthe,</hi> all which will make eight Troupes.</p>
            <p>One to be commanded by the Lord <hi>Balcarres,</hi> and to consist of the twelve score ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed to come out of <hi>Fyfe:</hi> of two Troupes to be levied, the two hundred horse appointed to come out of <hi>Kinkardin,</hi> and the Earle <hi>Marshalls</hi> part of <hi>Aberdene,</hi> and the twenty horse out of <hi>Forfar,</hi> before reserved from the Lord <hi>Gordon.</hi>
            </p>
            <closer>
               <signed>
                  <hi>Arch. Primerose</hi> Cler. Com.</signed>
            </closer>
            <pb facs="tcp:178894:2"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:178894:2"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>